refme.com 2016-03-22

# RefME | Privacy and Cookies Policy

RefME Limited (“we”, “us”, “our”) is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This Privacy and Cookies Policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us through www.refme.com (our “Website”), will be processed by us. It also describes how cookies are used on our Website and your rights in connection with such cookies. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

## About us

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is ReferenceME Limited a company registered in England and Wales with registration number 08894496 and registered office at RefME , Unit 9 New North House, Canonbury Business Centre, 202-208 New North Road, London, N1 7BJ.

## Other Applicable Terms

This Privacy and Cookies Policy refers to the following additional documents, which also apply to your use of our Website:

  * Our Terms of Use, which set out the terms on which you are permitted to use our Website and the service made available via our Website.
  * Our Software Licence Terms, which set out the terms which will apply if you choose to download from our Website and use our Web plugin.
  * The applicable app licence terms if you choose to download our RefME app from Google Play, iTunes or another app store.
  * Our Copyright and Intellectual Property Policy, which sets out the terms on which you can store and share journals and articles on our Website and the steps you can take if you are concerned that your copyright is being infringed by a someone using our Website.

### Information we may collect

We may collect and process the following information about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our Website, for the use of services, posting material, general enquiries or requesting further services.
  * Details of any journals, articles and papers which have been accessed by you including information about what use you make of those journals, articles and papers.
  * We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our Website or regarding the products and/or services provided by us.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfilment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to our Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

We may also take cache copies of journals, articles and papers which have been posted, distributed or reproduced by you on our Website to enable us to let you access your research from any device and to recommend content. You should ensure that you have obtained the necessary consents from the copyright owners to allow such copies to be taken. For more information about this, please see our Copyright and Intellectual Property Policy.

## Aggregate Data

With regard to each of your visits to our Website we may automatically collect the following information:

  * technical information, including the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and
  * information about your visit, including the full uniform resource locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our Website (including date and time); page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

We may collect this information for system administration, to report aggregated information to our advertisers or otherwise in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

## Cookies

Our Website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Website and also allows us to improve our Website.

## By using our website you are consenting to our use of cookies in accordance with this policy.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file stored by your web browser on your computer or mobile device. Some cookies are essential for our Website to work and help us provide you with relevant information. They also allow us to recognise your computer (but not specifically who is using it) when you access our Website and to improve the usability and performance of our Website.

### What do we use cookies for?

We use cookies to make our Website easier to use and to better tailor the online experience to your interests and needs. Cookies may also be used to help speed up your future activities and experiences on our Website. We also use cookies to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how people use our Website and to help us improve their structure and content. We cannot identify you personally from this information.

### We use the following cookies on our Website:

Cookie type  
Purpose  
User Login Cookies

These cookies are used to remember your login details where you have elected for your details to be remembered to avoid having to login each time you visit our Website.

### Turning off and deleting cookies

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. If you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser settings so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you access our Website. If you use different devices to view and access our Website (for example, your computer, smart phone, tablet etc.) you will need to ensure that each browser on each device is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences.

If you disable the cookies that we use this may impact your experience while on our Website.

### More Information about cookies

For more detailed information about cookies please visit www.allaboutcookies.orgwhich provides guidance on how to control cookies.

## Where We Store Your Personal Data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our business partners or suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## How we use your information

Information you give to us. We will use this information:

  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and/or services that you request from us;
  * to provide you with information about other products and/or services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
  * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about products and/or services we feel may interest you, where you have consented to such contact;
  * to notify you about changes to our Website;
  * to ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; and
  * for internal record keeping.

Information we collect about you. We will use this information:

  * to administer our Website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; and
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Website about products and/or services that may interest you or them.

Statistical information. We may use aggregate, statistical information regarding our users’ interests, courses, research and reading habits and we may share this information with publishers, universities and other third parties. This data will not contain any personally identifiable information.

Information we receive from other sources. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

### Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * such as our agents, suppliers, service providers and affiliates which assist us with operating our Website or providing related products or services or which assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Website;
  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * if ReferenceME Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers may be one of the transferred assets;
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use, Software Licence Terms or Copyright and Intellectual Property Policy or other agreements; or
  * otherwise in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy.

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by emailing us atprivacy@refme.com.

### Third party links

Our Website may, from time to time, contain links to other websites of interest. Please note, these websites have their own privacy and cookies policies and we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such websites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Access to information

The Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

If you believe that any information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us at privacy@refme.com

## Contact us

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy and Cookies Policy are welcomed. Please contact us at privacy@refme.com

Thank you for visiting our Website.
